Austin D. Brown | C.V.

Research Interests

My main research focus is on the analysis and computational efficiency of Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithms. Creating reliable, computational efficient Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithms for practitioners is the main motivation for my research. My other research interests are in optimal transportation, stochastic optimization, stochastic processes, and error-in-variable models.

My dissertation at the University of Minnesota "Some Convergence Results for Metropolis-Hastings Algorithms" focuses on the computational aspects of Metropolis-Hastings algorithms available here https://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/11299/243073.

Education

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

July 2017

Ph.D. in Statistics August 2022

Dissertation: "Some Convergence Results for Metropolis-Hastings Algorithms"

Advisor: Galin L. Jones

B.S. in Mathematics

Committee: Charles Geyer, Qian Qin, Wei-Kuo Chen

University of Florida Gainesville, FL

Major in Mathematics and minor in Statistics

Teaching Experience

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities	Minneapolis, MN
Instructor	Spring 2021

Introduction to Statistical Analysis (STAT 3011)

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Minneapolis, MN
Instructor Spring 2020

Regression and Correlated Data (STAT 3032)

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Minneapolis, MN

Teaching Assistant Fall 2021

Applied Statistical Methods 3 (STAT 8053)

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Minneapolis, MN

Teaching Assistant

Theory of Statistics 2 (STAT 4102)

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Minneapolis, MN

Teaching Assistant
Applied Statistical Methods 2 (STAT 8052)

pplied Statistical Methods 2 (STAT 6002)

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Minneapolis, MN
Teaching Assistant Fall 2018

Introduction to Probability and Statistics (STAT 3102)

Publications

[1] **Austin Brown** and G. Jones, "Exact convergence analysis for Metropolis–Hastings independence samplers in Wasserstein distances," *Journal of Applied Probability*, p. 1–22, 2023.

- [2] **Austin Brown** and G. Jones, "Lower Bounds on the Rate of Convergence for Accept-Reject-Based Markov Chains," *preprint https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.05955*, 2022.
- [3] **Austin Brown**, "Geometric Ergodicity of Gibbs Samplers for Bayesian Error-in-variable Regression," preprint https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08301 (Submitted to Electronic Journal of Statistics), 2022.
- [4] **Austin Brown** and G. Jones, "A Survey of Modern Convergence Analysis for Metropolis-Hastings," *In preparation for WIREs Computational Statistics*, 2024.

Conferences / Invited Talks

University of Warwick

Coventry, United Kingdom

Algorithms and Computationally Intensive Inference Seminar

January 2023

Fall 2020

Spring 2019

Talk Title: Lower Bounds on the Rate of Convergence for Accept-Reject-Based Markov Chains.

Slides: https://austindavidbrown.github.io/talk/warwick2023.pdf

University of Warwick

Wales, United Kingdom

University of Warwick Departmental Conference 2023

April 2023

June 2023

Talk Title: Exact convergence for independence samplers in Wasserstein distance.

Slides: https://austindavidbrown.github.io/talk/warwickdepartmental2023.pdf

University of Oxford

Bioinference 2023

England, United Kingdom

Poster Title: Geometric ergodicity of Gibbs samplers for Bayesian error-in-variable regression.

Poster: https://austindavidbrown.github.io/poster/bioinference2023.pdf

Statistical Software

cmhi: A Python package for the centered Metropolis-Hastings independence algorithm.

github.com/austindavidbrown/Centered-Metropolis-Hastings

mhlb: A Python implementation to estimate lower bounds on the geometric convergence rate for RWM Metropolis-Hastings. https://github.com/austindavidbrown/lower-bounds-for-Metropolis-Hastings

Book Editing

An Introduction to Envelopes, Dennis Cook

Jan 2019

Referee/Peer Review

Bayesian Analysis	2020
PLOS ONE	2022
Advances in Applied Probability / Journal of Applied Probability	2023
Sankhya, Series B	2023

Service

Organizer of University of Warwick Algorithms and Computational Intensive Seminar Jan 2023–

June 2023

University of Warwick Statistics Department IT Committee

2022-June 2023

University of Warwick Stonewall Self-Assessment Team (LGBTQ+ Inclusion) 2022–June

2023

Memberships

Institute of Mathematical Statistics

2022-Present

Scholarships and Awards

Beverly and Richard Fink Fellowship (\$56000+Tuition)	2017–2022
Lynn Lin Fellowship (\$2000)	2019–2019
First Year Scholarship (\$2500)	2017–2017

Extracurricular Activities

Markov Chain Monte Carlo Group (2019–2022)
 Discussion of the state of the art MCMC literature

Professional Experience

University of Toronto

Toronto, Ontario

Postdoctoral Researcher Advisors: Jeffrey Rosenthal July 2023–Onward

University of Warwick

Coventry, England

Research Fellow (Postdoctoral Researcher)

September 2022-June 2023

Advisors: Krzysztof Latuszynski and Gareth Roberts

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

Graduate Assistant/PhD Candidate

2017-2022

Projects and responsibilities:

- As a graduate instructor and teaching assistant, I developed course materials, taught lectures, and administered exams for undergraduate and graduate courses.
- Project title: I-net: Extending the elastic-net with I1 to I10 penalties in regression.
 - Abstract: We create an R package written in C++ to combine l^1 penalized regression with higher order l^p penalizations built upon the Elastic-net. The package is able to fit regression models with penalizations ranging from l^1 to l^{10} .
 - Link: github.com/austindavidbrown/l-net
- Project title: Confidence Intervals via Gaussian Policy Gradients as an Augmented Wasserstein Gradient Flow.
 - Abstract: We introduce a novel reinforcement learning model by reformulating the policy-gradient algorithm as an augmented Wasserstein gradient flow. This formulation leads to statistically valid confidence intervals when using Gaussian policies. We focus our applications on obtaining confidence intervals in supervised learning. In image classification on CIFAR10, our model performs comparable to existing approaches and on MNIST, our model outperforms existing reinforcement learning approaches.

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

Research Assistant

2020-2020

Project description: Applied Bayesian inference to deep learning for high-dimensional protein structure prediction.

o Principal Investigator: Singdhansu Chatterjee, NSF award: 1939956

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

Statistical Consultant

2019–2019

Statistical consultant for the Initiative Institute on the Environment at the University of Minnesota.

- Project title: Modeling Corn Yield by Temperature and Precipitation
- Description: Extreme temperature and precipitation prediction using deep Gaussian processes for the state of Minnesota.

University of Florida

Gainesville, FL

Full Time Student

2017

Lightmaker

Orlando, FL

Lead Mobile Software Engineer/Mobile Software Engineer

2012-2015

I engineered awesome mobile applications and assisted with optimization and performance of mobile websites.

- o Technologies used: Java, C, iOS, Java, Git.
- Notable projects:
 - Barclays ATP World Tour Finals;
 - Mayo Clinic;
 - AMC Extras iOS;
 - LPGA Android/iOS application;
 - Mcafee Partner iOS;
 - USGA Rules of Golf iOS/ Android;
 - Cherokee Casinos;
 - Hard Rock Tulsa;
 - Ikea:

Programming Languages, Frameworks, and Databases

Python: Pytorch, Autograd, Numpy, Matplotlib, Jupyter Expert

R: ggplot, Rmarkdown

SQL: Advanced

C++: C++14 specification and above, Eigen *Intermediate*

Java: Advanced

Languages

English (native)

Spanish (novice)

• French (novice)

References

- o Professor Galin Jones. University of Minnesota Twin Cities. Email: galin@umn.edu
- Assistant Professor Qian Qin. University of Minnesota Twin Cities. Email: qqin@umn.edu
- Associate Professor Krzysztof Latuszynski. University of Warwick. Email: K.G.Latuszynski@warwick.ac.uk